So,you guys watch the keynote this morning and saw the
...craft them make a little reference to that today the talk is about visual studio
and visual studio online extensibility when we actually started on that talk the title
...the seven words shorter so I don't know what happened to it over
a period of last week's can expanded but it's mainly about visual studio
...visual studio linux and extensibility my name is
...math where...the group program manager for the visual studio tocore id team
which is responsible for the editing and building and like core
...experience for visual studio for all languages and my first-time actually to
have multiples because...states is...be funI...my from the visual studio
online team is the program manager undersea...and...here with
one of...vp sabharwal...who's also a one of our community members
people contributing to visual so-you accessibility we're all going to be talking to you about how to create extensions for
real studio and for visual studio line so we got started.
Also mandatory slide about apparently evaluations a I hear that
the higher the score that you put...evaluation the...your chances of winning a
...only for this talk.
All right so we'll just the do very quickly why work and extensibility and
just I want to set the stage for...one understand how many of you are existing
visual studio extensibility developers currently have an extension create...as
a handful so maybe like ten percent of audio sorry well that's good how many of you are interested?
Gladys all of you as a good
...visual see online anybody dabbling with visual studio...
All...expected great anybody already creating extensions diversity...
...all right you guys are
winners ok so I'll talk a little bit about
...why extensions this session is not
a three hundred four hundred level you're ready and extension developer I'm going to
teach about all the new api eyes and, you know, go through, through them one by one this is really
intended for the majority of the audience here which is I'm interested in visual see extensibility want to
...more about it as...talk to-you about accessibility why do it what you can do with it
we'll talk about...visual studio aspect and the visual studio line aspect for those of
...ready extension developers we're going to be talking about some of the new stuff on visual
studio...and what you can do as a current visual studio accessibility developer on visual
...but it's mostly targeted ad if you're interested in the topic
you want to know more about it so that's kind of the level that we're going to be apps just to set expectations if you're looking at the
re-re deep level api stuff we actually recorded some sessions
on video so that you...refer to them at the end of the talk and you can go and watch a
...talk more about the nitty-gritty of api...and how to do things
right so we'll talk a bit about the high-level of what is possible then we'll go
...two sections one is going to be about the visual studio client and how
we can extend that...is going to be about visual studio line...how you can extend that...
all-star quickly with what is an extension so extensions are basically ways to
customize are developing environment as developers we like to control how're environment
works we spend a lot of time in our environment and,
you know, everything from the colors the to the keyboard
shortcuts
...certain behaviors of how things do we like to customize all of those things extensions
provide you with a way to do these customizations for yourself but also allow
you to give those customizations to people and you can go all the way from like doing the simple things of adding,
you know, a little code snippet and giving it to everybody to use all the way
to having a project system that handles java so, for example, this morning when you so
...crafts that mine craft demo is all about if you noticed is about java development
and...happening in visual studio but if you also realize visual studio doesn't really do javaso,
how was it done well extensions and?
Actually same right here is the one that authored a java extensions in visual studio allows you to
edits build and debug java code from without within visual studio so we were looking
at creating extension for
...craft instead of redoing that work we built on top of says extension to do a
java so...extensions building on top of each other some nice way to not only
customized but also and, modify functionality in the visual studio id.
The way that those extensions...get authored and then go to other
people's that you publish them to the visual studio gallery you
can also actually handle them as deployment bits we call them
bsix packages we can create packages and give other people but traditional way that you would give it to somebody and
make it available to a lot of people is by putting it on the visual studio gallery so as an extension author
we give you access to...visual study gallery upload your extension managed updates change
versions do all of that stuff and then you'll be able to also in the gallery see the feedback
...the ratings for your for your thing the feedback...this coming in from user eventually going to be able to see a
lot more like crash data and things like that so it's a it's kind of a rich experience targeted
...but then on the consuming side every developer...you know,
millions of developers using visual studio every developer guess access...visual...gallery and they can go and
browse that and...extension...right and it also be able to.
Tell you how good it is or what you need to improve...right?
From inside visual studio there's also an experienced...extensions so there's
an extensions the...where you can go and view one of the most popular extensions and
...revamping this experience...so this kind of a preliminary experience that we ship
...the last release and kind of keeping up for this time around but
...looking at improving this experience and everybody used to be the only
...professional visual
studio enterprise that would be able to get access to those extensions
...with about six months ago I think we're...visual studio community
and visually community is open to is a free version is also open to be using
...extensions so now...people if
you're creating extensions every single visual to developer almost every single visual
...developer has access has the ability to access
...extensions it's a much wider audience than we've ever had before so,
we're glad to have that...it's a great-great way of
a larger ecosystem and making all the customizations all...
modifications that you're doing available to every single visual...developer right so now
visually community has that support and for visual twenty fifteen obviously we're continuing with that?
In addition to the visual studio traditional visual studio
extensibility which is...allowed us to give that
...additional features and now we have is to the online and
visually align is basically the targeted at teams working together so
way to collaborate over codes and collaborate overwork
in general and,we're now enabling you to
have extensibility not only in visual studio client but also on visual studio
line itself and are many scenarios and that kind of spend both the work
for you individually as a developer working on your machine eight hours a day doing
something but also we have a component where as a team you want to see something, you know, whether it's a
code review tool where you want to see some changes
on the developer client and be able to see something on a team room or whether it is
a some analysis that is happening on a continuous integration you wanna-be able to see those results individuals
to id even learned lots of scenarios where you're going to see both of them happening together so,
for example, this is just a snapshot of my own visual studio
...page where I can get to create repositories and projects and share them with
other people and collaborate on them so you can actually customize...experience and...going to talk about that more detail?
basically it's a obviously online covers everything from the code itself and how it works
in the build...the build management configuration of that all the way to the testing of its
and deployment of it and...having insights on it to work item tracking and source code
management...basically a full experience...the lifecycle of your application so we allow you to
customize every single part of that that's our goal right so today we're going to tell you about how to do
this but why do...be questions why do the
...a bunch of motivated people coming here I'm glad that, you know, all of you raise your hand
...said who is interested in doing it that's great...many reasons why people are interested in doing this
number one reason is actually for you and for your team like when we
talk to developers why did you start customizing visual studio first thing they say is
there was something I wanted to do I could into in visual studio I asked you guys didn't do it so I
...myself?
And,...we ask people to tell us what they...we have user voice and we go ask people to vote
and things and user voice and some things you just you can see it but you don't necessarily everybody
lcs it just doesn't...are radar so you go to it and, you know,
what by,... get that, you know, giving you that ability you get to creates
the demand and that need and then you help all...developers so this was a from a blog post comment
...a blog post from just a few weeks ago this person right there was saying
hey feature requests I would love it if you guys do this now think...from our
rc just shipped you guys couple days ago and we made it available to our
...vp maybe just a little while shorter than that so two weeks ago we were about ready to finish the
last finishing touches on that product and but it out the market here's somebody coming us with
a feature requests...be really nice visual
...fifteen had that there's no way in the next two days we're going to be able to look at this and make
it happen butts with visual to the extensibility
...absolutely make that what is being requested hear something that is open easy to do
as a visual studio extension somebody could just do that and then, you know, letting go from there?
Another reason is ...you have a certain you already have a product that you that is
...a developers or you have you want to create a product that started...developers visual
studio has millions of people that would be able to see it so that's one way to get your idea your
...out to a lot of people to see money and...fame
...so how do you how do you get all that audience and
the one of the things that you can do extensions are not fully free there are paid extensions well they're actually a number of companies
...them I can see here...audience or making the money off of a
extensions to visual studio and, it's a thriving ecosystem is something that you can play...as well?
If you go in the third-floor you...to find a...for visual studio industry partners and
they're all people that are actually participating in our
...system and...are great set of people to not only go learn about what is it that
they're doing that could help use developer they're set of people to also talk to about what their
experience is building visual studio accessibility solutions and they
would be very happy to talk to-you about not only their solution but also what it took them to
creating the afterall all developers...real to help each other so, that's something to do.
Last is.
Creating you know, that sense of...
Think of it as a like that's one thing that we're starting to do now is you creating your learning
...you skill and one of the best ways to learn
...new skill is to learn it with other developers and
...one of the things that we're pushing for right now is a for a lot of things to be
open-source and you've seen you know, you know throughout the key notes yesterday
and today of a lot of stuff being pushed online to get harbour to some other open-source
repository and the this is one great way of learning...scale so you want to learn about
...extensibility want to see how it's done...creating open-source project
go started and go have people collaborate on it and the fun thing is when we actually started looking at the
statistics for visual studio extensions a lot of them are actually being
...open-source quite a number of fact the top twenty about fifty percent is already
open-source available to you that you can go learn from contribute to whatever it is that you want so
that's another thing that is that...enjoyable as a developer
...to belong to communities that...a nice and healthy thriving community that you can be part.
This is actually a cool extension I was browsing the community stuff and the
accession that I saw was this one is called the encourage
visual studio and the sole purpose in life is when you save.
It gives you...message
...you job...something you need that smiling your day, you know,
after working hard and something for somebody the baggio the backs of this was apache...was created by a
...hacker actually works...get up and the fun extension I thought it was really cool
he actually open-source that extension or his number one request was can-you customize
the messages that are being there so he added tools options extensibility people have them do that and now
you could actually some read like if you don't like the encouraging messages anyone to you know,
some other types of encouragement you've got that too so lots of cool things that you can actually build with
a...until them if I show it here that, you know,
everybody's going to go download it's called visit encourage, encourage you to downloaded very...
All right so that's enough...encouragement abouts the visual city
extensibility what I really wanted to get today is actually and how to do that what
is possible in the world of visual studio extensibility so I'm going to start by introducing sam
...sam is a lead engineer at the synopsis working on
...also has a lot of extensions ffour visual
studio of java is one of them of course but he's got a lot more he's going to talk to-you
about some of them he's a very experience developer obviously sensibilities I thought,
you know, the me talking about it actually get somebody from our community talk to-you about it and...telly how...goes
...take away from...thank you dirk?
Sorrows give-me-a-call on april...
And, they said we're going to put the...craft.
Demo in our keynote.
And, we're going to put you in a session right after it and, we're going to give
you twenty minutes and we want you to explain how it works.
There's two groups of people in
here there are people that know it is impossible.
Because you're already in extension developer and the rest of you literally don't care.
So, you'll be happy...here that
...said no I would love to come onstage I love doing extensions but,
you know,...this is a group that came to learn we're going to give them some practical information and
show that visual studio extensions.
Means something for them in their job.
So, I...turned around.
The demo that you see today.
I thought of while I was driving to the airport to come here.
I developed it on a nonstop flight from boston to san francisco.
And, took a two-and-a-half-hour nap.
And, you're actually going to want to results.
Bold statement I'm hoping that lives up.
So, I actually do get this question a lot there's a lot of people that say I get this question is made up now people
really do wonder what can you extend you can literally extend anything.
...demo...software mine...yes I made it I did not make it for
...I was doing research in java
...static analysis software at college and,
I didn't like anything but visual studio team and they said hey that looks good for my craft
so yes you can do pretty much anything on a simple scale you can create a new command.
You can added tool window both of
these are very common things that actually a pretty easy to do now adding a debug are visualize or.
If you have a particular data type that you want to show
in a different way I've done some really cool things here I had a data type that what was a
block of tax that was.
Xml and it was hard-to-read and emait certainly couldn't read in the tool tip I wrote a
debug are...that could take this xml format and put into an html
format was suitable for display in debugging so I could quickly get an
overview of the contents of this data structure and plugged in that's easy.
That html visualize are all I had to do was
...html...html string.
Inside the class so I happen to know what the visualize or was it was a
targeted case and now I was able to debug this type much easier.
You can add a refactoring option this used to be possible but difficult.
With roslyn in early cp is a visual studio
twenty fifteen which has since been improved I did six of them in one
day for
targeted business requirements that are only relevant to the team that I was working on at the time.
Manual things that I did
during code review anyone could verify automatically at that point.
These are going to be meaningfulyou might not
use them today a year from now this is going to be a standard part of your
workflow and you will probably be using ones that nobody else is just for your project.
I've been pushing back so, I don't work for microsoft word for...verity I do I'm
a lead on the desktop experience.
I make sure...expert their extensions work well for your environment I've
been pushing back on microsoft regarding the whole experience for extension
developers for a while now and several teams have come to me
and we've been working to improve your experience from the day you start to the...ship.
And, some of the ways that we've done is
the new practical templates not one project where you
create you create some sample and it has one static set of features and if you want to
do anything else.
Well, you've got some samples there to start with good luck.
No, it's actually you can start with nothing
and you can add the features you want you will see that and then.
You have a project...contains exactly what you intended.
Open-source extensions.
This used to be open-source samples one of the most valuable things about
...extension is people care about it they
use it and they're going to maintain it and it's going to stay relevant.
These are things that are going to solve problems you care about in ways that you
probably want to look at and understand so.
Tarts been working with heather I'm sorry I don't know her last
name I just recently found out yesterday
...they're gathering a list of all these open-source extensions and you're going to be able to quickly
reference them in addition to the samples that are available already available cloning
go this is something that I actually implemented in combination with...jared
...visual studio team if you go and you want to use one of
my open-source extensions and you go to get hub and you four-k...hit clone on copies it
to your machine if you open it in visual studio and hit f five.
That's it...working will launch visual studio the extensions running
...it's a particularly valuable
experience and it does not matter what version visual studio you open it in
two thousand ten plus they're kind of work exactly like what I just said.
Many of them use mit and
apache to licenses this means in addition to being able to reference that you can take the code you can use it in europe.
Friendly faces friendly people I love working with new extensions most
of the people that use...extension that I had a part of I didn't create the
extension I didn't come up with the idea my name is maybe in a footnote.
But, I enjoyed having a role in making sure it was polish for everybody to use.
I'm going to start moving much faster.
Targeting multiple versions visual studio this is absolutely critical at my job my
extension that I'm currently working on it co very targets visual studio twenty-five and
newer and we want a positive experience regardless of the environment that you're in we have
a pretty well-established set of ways that you can extend visual studio two thousand
ten and newer and I'm really working to bring those into the templates for the community be
able to use they're not part of visual studio yet but they are already open-source
and, if you're looking for that for your particular projects the information is coming.
New api are old it doesn't matter you use the ones that
you need most of my extensions target older versions of visual studio as well I use the
older api as I do want to highlight a few api is that are coming in twenty
fifteen that are making me a little sad that I can't just use those all the time.
Rather than analyzers they're awesome.
Specific targeted diagnostics whether it's style or semantics plus refactoring
...your project.
We currently have probably a hundred of them and production.
...awesome light bulbs roslyn...analyzers time...service but,
you can actually use light bulbs to put any information you want
their image service visual studio
twenty fifteen is the first id that's going to have full complete support for
high dpi monitors all of the icons in visual studio twenty fifteen have been rework
...all vector graphics it is gorgeous we do not have anything onstage that
can show it but next year we will and it's going to be there for
us...actually great asynchronous service provider they
double...performance again in two thousand fifteen
it's obvious even in rc builds that it's faster the asynchronous service provider
extends allows extension developers to tap into some of those performance advantages
...project system is a project system that's been used internally
by microsoft since two thousand ten it is it getting documentation and
...nice public face with two thousand fifteen you're going to be able to use it add new project
...visual studio.
...rule-based ui context engine which I have not used
and don't know about but it sounds cool?
We have manage to use the vsi x packaging is the new
packaging for visual studio extensions to deliver pretty much any extension you
can come up with you put them in the gallery somebody can search in visual studio find it
download it run it and it's going and in recent builds since two thousand twelve
it'll tell you when there's upgrades available and you click it it's a it's a per user installation
no admin required and you can get the extensions that you need for your job and you're
going to go quality unmatched performance they continue to work on performance we've been working on
performance for extensions for a number of ways high dpi support.
Mention that revisiting localization how many of you have actually worked on a product that needed to ship
and more than one language how many of you try to do with...visual studio extension.
...completely rewriting that it was pretty it was important
to verity and we're working to bring some of that back...so
...you don't have to worry about the command localization within the past.
And, tarred mentioned community addition so.
I have five minutes to do what I promised a whole lot of you I would do.
...I'm amazing edit or I'm going to run maybe two three minutes over.
I notice was preparing for demonstrations a common problem.
When you zoom in visual studio only the editors zooms?
Nothing else.
In particular how many of you saw a quick info in the keynote when
...tip how many of you could read that.
You...got there like six am.
My extension makes it where when you zoom it
ties together all the different things that you can zoom.
It seems obvious right all right so,
yes, this is a small idea a
targeted application not necessarily something you're going to use every day
but absolutely meaningful this is a great candidate for an extension.
So, what I'm going to start
...is I will go and I will?
Create a new gab repository and we will call it and presentation
Is there but I'm supposed to push?
This part wasn't told...presentation mode for visual...I can't do this...I'm sorry.
You'll be happy to...mit license this.
And, I will not make it a private repository.
we put it on to varies organizationwith the predefine
get ignore create all right and I now have a repository.
Creativeness solution.
This is one of the things.
They told me they made new templates for this and I was like
I don't like using templates I'm one of those people that I'm not going to use word to make html documents
...the output it's a little noisy for me this is a great template.
Vsi x project what is a come with.
Nothing except manifest.
No, references nothing.
...product id we...product name were good.
License.
All right that's the file that was created by the get have extension when I created the
repository.
We have to commands that we want to add.
Increase font-size.
When I do this everything gets set up automatically it added all the references that
needed to be added it configured...build so that it's going to package it up as a
...it added my bs package for extension developers, you know,
what I'm talking about the rest if you are really happy that you don't need to
do this simple as that?
This is actually a really complicated process.
via ct file was created it added my new extension there we're going to give it a new
...actually going to say when it shows up on a menu it's going to be called increase font-size.
We're going to go to
the tvs package and I'm going to use another extensibility feature.
I was a little sleepy on this.
...good thing I don't actually have to...this method right.
Adjusting the font-size actually uses several of the visual studio api is that
...not specifically going to go into but it is going to be open-source...to reference this.
Is a fun color storage service I basically told it get the current
font increase the font-size by whatever the changes?
Or decreases and...apply it to specific categories
all right now I go over to my increase font-size.
It added a command...is so much easier than it used to be
handle increase.
...all right so when we execute the command all we need to do is.
Increase the font-size and this is my increase command so will increase it by two points.
So, basically to adjust the font-size for all those different categories in fonts and colors that you would
have had to go manually to just to say you're font-size all
...now one of
the cool things adding a new command do the same thing for decrease and it's much faster.
So, when did this it reuse the same...the same command table?
And, it just created only the necessary additions in order to add
...add this particular command so, the
add command feature ads only the necessary requirements to add the specific...
The naming of the package by default is a little weird.
But, that's okay all right so that's it.
If...run this.
If your extension developer, you know, that actually this is also something used to have to configure.
Every step that I did
today used to be about ten steps in the past this was literally
...and impossible presentation ever before.
Building...loading.
And, I know it works because I'm actually using it so that you can see what I was doing there.
I told myself run...debugging.
Another project ...another open-source project I did just randomly for fun
who you cannot see at all what it is?
...I knew that was going to happen something changed in this
bill all right that's it in addition you can see that code
lens increased in font-size.
And, you can see the...
The conclude completion drop down increased...font-size.
That's all right.
Would?
This product practiced it will go-fast.
I promise this part to bunch of people.
Visual studio gallery.
Close...
Everything is prepared for you when you create a package.
...location.
I have to do on the visual studio gallery is upload it I'm uploading a tool.
I would like to upload my...
We have to skip this step.
I missing you sorry.
I'll try to have...published by the time you leave your anyway so,
I will do one more thing the changes I made changes.
Comment push pushing live is currently live.
...enjoyed it thank you thanks.
So, but, you saw how ...was able to go from you think of
an idea to go created to publish it created...
Try to put in the gallery missing a little...
But, almost there and the thing is the in lots of extension developers
a few...here lots of people are interested extensions this is to be a really hard thing to do
mean everybody who's worked with accessibility ready knows how a...areas
...for this release really putting a big emphasis on extensibility we're starting with beefing
up the sdk the documentation the samples presence on get hub
opensource getting everything that is open-source available to so you can see it encouraging you and having
away for you to creature stuff and open-source you just...get hub extension for visual studio
...we just-released with rc makes it easier for you to go and do that as well as
so the gallery or...gallery subtle number of things that we're doingfor making
...better in visual studio twenty fifteen so it's really a very good time to be
an extension developer in visual studio so that was focused on the...to declined the new thing
that we're also adding is now with visual studio online or enabling new ways of extensibility
for the visual city community and here ...going to talk to-you about how to do that but
...also a tethered actually with a cable to this thing I'm serious
...is the cable so he can't move...is just sagan there,
you know, why?
Okay,...back...
Okay, so, I'm going to go through a few slides pretty quickly I do essays
in the new cool stuff that we're doing on...so side for extensibility we've
sort of announced stuff, you know, the last couple of days related to so,
this...extensions for via so we've already had some any
...and...actually star building some stuff and
...initially...some examples of that we're pretty excited about this because it brings a lot of the same
sort of concepts and ideas that you have in ds clients today for building extensions and kind
of extending your development environment and brings that same kind
of concept india so...fs as well.
Okay, so,you just in a high level,
you know,...we think about you know-how people are building software today
it's deliver software really requires a lot of different tools for a lot of different chains,
you know, if we...teams we talked to a small team to talk to organizations
...pretty common...is that they're not just using one stack of tools
their nudges using tf asses this sort of back into manage all
...different development projects using different tools...have a team its using...sort
of lightweight management of the tasks and work...doing your...if they...
applications in builders job applications using things like...
Tools...user voice forgetting user feedback and...
Tools for collaboration like slack.
...people to their using a lot of different tools as a delivering software.
We want-to make sure that if you're using visual studio online or using...fast they you
can weave together all these tools...create your own sort-of perfect development
environment so again just like in visual studio client where you can kind of
...different extensions in the...buy something for a partner you just get...from
the from the gallery from open-source we want to enable that same type of ecosystem that
same kind of customization visual studio online as well as...
So, we don't want to stuff over the last year sort of on the integration
side because really when it comes down to it all this...just talked about customization
...sort of a perfect development environment starts with the ability for
...integrate with our services so
...actually programmatic the integrate with via so through
...through api eyes so what we lashes we announced
...delimited bunch of rest api is there's a whole bunch of rest api for interacting
now of esl aps forgetting your work items and builds and that kind of
stuff we also introduce something called service irks which is basically a way to kinda
send messages between services so...you do something india so like checking code you can have
a send a message off to another service...the kick-off some of the workflow?
...sort of extension of that no pun intended really is to
start really delivering and allowing you to build even deeper
more richer experiences integration experiences with india so in dvs.
So, this
step and you can do up until now was I would say pretty basic you can build some nice
...of services service integrations the...ions through service sucks the
...announcing at build for building extensions is really going to
enable you to build much deeper richer integrations
so integrations where instead of users flipping between four or five
different browsers for five different services to get the information they need.
It's all brian together it's, you know,
available...context so if I'm looking
...they don't have to flip over to another windowed to go look at another services
build information I can see that build information...my idea so experience.
So, I mention most...this already...a skip it for now is four-time we
have delivered a bunch of...api as we continue to deliver rest api is.
The one really important point to make here is that all the rest
...developed and delivered so far...been exclusively esl.
But,...with the rc...twenty fifteen rc all those api
is are available in dvs on prime as well
...the same api set between via so in pdfs.
Service folksI'm actually show you a quick example of this.
...I...tenuous.
Service...is something that we added lashing that's also coming
...fs twenty fifteen as well and,
it's going to be what kind of enables very quick integration between
...and other services that whenever you check
...build gets completed you can have
...drives some other action or some other sort of process
on another service.
...quick demo of this you can kinda get better sense of service irks switch here.
Zooming okay,
so, how many people use or know of slack?
Sl ack okay quite a few so we work with slack in the
lashing to build...direct integration between via and slack.
And, this is another thing that will be nt...twenty fifteen rc as well.
So, when I can do with the integration using service circuses I can say hey let's say I
have a channel here and I make sure to go to an empty channel where no other people who are at posit
...densely before and when I can do and...I can say for this galego
...integration I want to be able to say that?
...here slide visual studio aligns by integration.
...it's going to do is it's going to give me a url here semantic a channel.
Give-me url...I just need to go plug into the sl.
So, what I can do now is I can flip over to the sl if
you haven't seen this before it's pretty cool a different encourage you to try it out if
you're project administrator you go into your admin?
There's a new sort
...service x cabin again this will be in twenty fifteen rc as well as
service x tab you can basically define what we call subscriptions was just
a way to say hey when something happens.
Do something over here so we support of a whole bunch
of services out-of-the-box this list is going to get bigger as we go?
But, I can take slack.
Hit next.
And, I can say okay whatever, you know,
build completes code gets push...our team is this we, you know,
have a subscript says hey when code is pushed to this repo we want to know about in a
are slight channel?
What I'm going to do for this is an say...getting...created without any filters
...want to go ahead and just post message out to that channel and slack?
Okay,
so,...my subscription for this project if I now flip back over here.
...menu part of backlog item what should happen if everything...is I should see
...message pop open in
...so this is kind of a simple example you could imagine a
lot more interesting sort of complex examples that you can do through service
...for example, if use what I have a custom service...kind of receiving sort of
a jasonkeath payload version of those events...driving some internal process
you can do all that to the web hook service that we offer but for a team
...using slack or using some other collaboration tool.
They can get also notifications as things are happening in the projects is the team
...kind of keep up-to-date with things.
So, that was...now service irks.
People play
...service...pretty cool feature ok soflip that will quit.
So, I can talk.
Okay, good.
Ok, so, in some real quick about extensions and in audio quick demo that
So, just like...client where enabling extensions for esl and
...fast and you can kind of think of this in the same...you can think about visual studio
...extensions we microsoft him basically the final set of places that
you can plug into and we're going to expand this list over time?
...now the focus is really
on web extensibility so a lot of the places where you can plug-in right now if you
...go...role in the early preview that we have...you can plug into a lot of
the context menus you can plug into a sort of the upper area there we can plug-in new
...as we call them but,...we...to go with this is we really want to...beyond those extension
points...those contribution points and...kind of...
support things like custom-built tasks...kind of...server-side functions.
But, just like with visual studio...
we want to get to the place where we can enable developers to test an extension
...in this case is going the actual production via so...and...on
...published that extension to essential gallery where other
users can then finals extensions in easily install them into their via so accounts.
So, we have some...I think it might we'll probably be putting more information out there
...future about kind of where we want to go with this
but a high-level you can imagine media is an account user can go
and discover extensions that are available to me...to my corporate
...gallery or the public gallery and
...install those extensions into my via so accounts and everybody now my via so
account has access to that new functionality...extension is provided.
this real quick...I will show...
...flip back here.
...through this really a kind of a high-level just to kinda give you a sense of things so
via so extension is simply a manifest just
like vsix with content.
right now that's that content actually needs to be published in hosted
...a server on a web server like agile website or roku or even a local server if
...developing but the manifest...as kind of describes
the basic information about the extension a has things like.
Sort of...the aidid...version
...description and some other information about the person.
In the case and the
aso extension we have to kinda know where to go actually pull in your static content like your html
yours new javascript css stuff like that so you can reference that from...extension manifest.
But, then really...really more interesting is
within your manifest you also then specify a set of contributions and
contribution is basically something like an action or hub or something
and we define...twenty five.
Contribution points that you as an extension developer can basically
plug into...reach contribution point you have to specify certain fields
...names...kind of required by that contribution point.
So, in this example in this act in this example actually exist and get so,
you go to microsoft organization...get hub
gear so extensions samples you can actually get to this code.
This...a very simple extension that lets you extend the current
branches menu in via so with a new main menu option that lets you easily
...branch so we don't have like a...click
on branch option today in the via so web experience to the leader branch and basically
...delete up to the server.
So, this is simply just contributing
a new action to this get branches tree actions menu.
And, it's going to...run some code that we have
is all javascript here.
We have...quite a few other examples actually a type script so we have a whole set
...script ...files that we include that you can use to kind of make...code your application.
So, if I go and install this...that experience looks like real quick.
So, if I go
...my account level extensions talmud I can do is I can go install this extension.
So, right now.
Siosism.
Right now you just have to simply upload your manifest file again it's kind of referencing
...your static content in this case eye-hand static content all living...as your website.
And, now I've...that...esl accounts so now anybody in my
...so account has that new capability annette new capability
is I flip over here to my code hub and refresh.
Should have a new delete action now in my in my context
many so this in exist before eigen now?
Selected advantages like the javascript...
And,...and,
what this does is...uses are rest api is actually go to...apprehension
...page to refresh so pretty simple extension but and just like the extensions that
you can build for visual studio client there's a lot of really cool powerful things that you can do in a
very short time that you could never have done before?
So, pretty, pretty...you can do theirI
...to show one more quick example.
Because this is an app that we've actually made available as well.
So, it's funny I was I was at the booth yesterday talking to people
...over to another booth and they were talking about via so and.
The connell was...be great if I had like a team calendar from my team india so it'd be great if I
can, you know, have all the events that...my team and see everything kind of an account of...like that's kind
of interesting we actually had...the demo sort of showcase extension
that actually is just that so in this codes...and get have if you...look at it?
But, it's basically a very simple.
...calendar so if I go back over here this code and
...I showed you this is a little bit morecomplicated complex but,
it's the same idea there's an extension manifest.
For this team calendar extension...contributing a...you'll see here in a minute.
And, what's really cool also about this particular extension is the fact that it's
kind of been designed to be extended so...kind of hurt your brain here.
I talked about contribution points is kind of places that you can plug new...I'm inside
devious a web experience extensions can also defined contribution
poinsettia other extensions can contribute to and that's exactly what this calendar extension
is doing its both providing functionality but it's also opening up at a point where
...extensions can actually plug-in capability or new
events sources in the case...this.
Example.
Okay, so, I installed it
...so the right one we'll find out.
So, the team calendar.
Contributor hub.
Which shows up here...the home area?
And, what this is a simple cali...so we're using...opensource
calendar javascript library called full calendar and what it's doing is
it's making rest calls so it's actually calling the rest api that we have to get
...sprint dates it showing you those dates it's getting all my teams
...showing that information here I can add free-form events
...storing
...information in my sort-of...special...storage area?
And, then now anybody my team can go in here see
...the events see what's going on with the spread so again just a simple example it's adding get...the microsoft
...if you're interested in seeing...actually playing with it you can actually pulling
extension manifest and upload q india so account and play with this today if you...
So, let me continue on here I
wanted to talk real quick anyone running at a time but I do want to highlight.
I mention that, you know, we've had some
...and partners actually start using this stuff they've been using it for a few sprinter
a few months now and some really cool stuff is already been developed so,
this first example is from
...dev is one of our recent...a really cool tool to the
baseline kind of analysis tool that's now plugged into the sl
you can do a lot of they have a lot of really good capabilities that now instead of sitting sort
of outside india so outside of dvs now sit within the sl ...here you can go talk to them
...nca see this action.
Jeff levinson of former...now
...pm built something called work item visualize are so this is a really cool
way...sort of visually understand linkages between work...again
...extension making use of the rest api...information.
And, then just a quick example obviously whereas built
...impact analysis tool...
it's kind of on top of sort-of your planning process and your work items...can kind of define
sort of impacts of a particular work item...different categories.
Their here's well actually I think they're, they're not here this week
they'll be chicago next week but pretty cool to another good example of an
extension that is using this new extensibility framework that we built for...
Ok.
lots of places to get your and here a lot less places star here so.
We have this sort of a combined bs integration
site so you...microsoft
...extend the...and...get you to this extensibility site that we have.
So, if you're...bs...interesting...extending ...
serbia so that's kind of places start...mention that there's a video or maybe
...videos...on that created for...a deep
...doing abs id extension that's out there now.
Visio gallery which you probably mostly familiar with is also
new area that's just come online last couple of days adding get hub
has basically is one of the beginnings of a new extensibility community
...basic...area where you building...extension for bs esl.
Able to basically registered out there put
it out there other people belly easily discover other open-source
...extensions in that place.
So, we have the code challenge...then can challenge?
Okay, there's like a lot of people...somebody had done
that since there if you're interested in playing with like the
extensions stuff for the sl.
It's currently in private preview if you join the
ds partner program you'll get early access to
...extensions capability...to be set program dot com slash join
or you can just walk over to their booth there's also a bunch of visual studio partners you have any visual
studio partners here few.
So, there's booths third-floor kinda near the microsoft
boosts you can see a lot of these tools
...possible see...via so extensions of also been developed.
Okay.
So, I know we wanted to have.
A few minutes for questions.
Have approximately one-minute...course we always
stay after to ironing questions in the from here to...sand?
So, the question is will be able to use any of the universal app
controls from inside the visual studio you can use.
A you can use...
Traditional as...controls you can
do universal app controls yet but, as that as some of that stuff, you know,
they talk this morning about moving some of that stuff to traditional...controls as some of that
...shows up you get...be able to users to you but not...once network made for you aps.
The question of the...love to see some...to write that...
Yeah, so, the question is a some extensions don't play very well with other...for example,
give...of the...so there are two ways to do with this so one is guidance from
microsoft so one of the things that we're working on is for extension developers creating some
...but another thing and...probably the most effective way is the way for
you as a customer and extension to be able to...feedback to extension developers and
go tell them about...what is a problem with extension or how it's behaving with one thing where the other ads?
Yeah, so,I think the way that we're we think that all of that feedback should
...should be in the
extension itself on its page on the gallery so there should be a...on the gallery where
...community should be able to go and say...it breaks with this and it doesn't work with that and,
you know, and, either translate that into bugs or translate that into work-arounds
...translate that into something...have a...for the community to talk about and extension on
that extensions place to collaborate with it so that's what we're going to enabling with updates the...
There's a lot ofI'm just curious why the tight and sense mining so are
you have some...developers can get mining out of developing extension.
I'm not sure I understood...again
...either...mining being so the up some beeps on
...developers skin get mining as.
...tips about how developers get money so I think the best think
to doctor would be to talk about some of our partners that already exist that do make money off of business to
do so walk around the third for talk to the...and see what their ideas are for business model
I think the best thing is to actually have something that developers would want to use and then
...best that is get good reviews on the gallery and what we're going
to be working on is making sure that things...actually get good reviews are featured or
...now the galleries kind of hidden place not shown in the rest of id we're going to bring that
front and forward and make sure that if you develop something that is valuable will make sure the
developers do seats I think that it starts with a good idea and then it goes from
there the important thing is going to your business model and how to think about it but that's less about visual studio
accessibility and more about any business that your...
Yeah, so, that.
The question is a very plan for commerce so,you can have centralized payment and
it's on a road map...so one of the common things that we do in fact with the bringing of visual studio
online it's more even of a necessity because with visual studio you could still have that, you know,
...by website go downloaded from added...actually added to visual studio
...there's not that equivalent of go downloaded binary and,...may
be essential...maybe just to do with...so we are actually considering doing that
were in the investigation phase of what with...how would look...something that's
in our road map we want to be able to enable it such that as a developer you go say this...want...what I want this is why
...to...payments handle all of that so, it's definitely...
Anyplace to...his...extensible tvs code it's not it's not there yet but,
absolutely on our road map so it actually
it's very interesting because the yesterday as we announced that, you know, what people went to user voices...adding stuff on
...last I checked...were more than a hundred...requests of previous code
at last night as of...pm when I looked at it the number
one request by far was can-you please at accessibility to that so I know that's definitely a
roadmap and having it top...user voices only going to accelerate that I assume?
All right we'll thank you very much really appreciate your presence...